We see that the entire digestive system is well suspended at the base of the skull.
This means there is a very important movement called the movement between the sacrum and the occiput,
which is a movement of life, a movement of balance that supports health.
If I have too much tension here, I can disturb my cranial-sacral system.
sacral.
This means we have here your sternum, and we have
seen that ultimately,
the embryo made a global movement in its development where the pivot point
was expressed
on my sternum, which means that not only do I have a cranio-sterno-sacral system,
but we will
add later in the cranio-sterno-sacral development the mandibular aspect
which is also a phase of expansion,
which is also a phase of retraction, which is also a phase of inspiration,
which is also the phase
of expiration. The teeth, the base of the teeth, will influence,
will provide the mapping of the base
of the skull, which contains, I remind you, in this sphenoidal plane, a gland
that, in relation to
my epiphysis, is a gland that supports hormonal processes. This
means that it is an axis
global on my entire hormonal plane. We are hormonal beings. We are
completely dependent on our glands.
Epiphysis,
pituitary,
thyroid,
adrenal, gonadal.
This axis is fundamental.
There is also something
that is very important, it's to understand well
the balance between
my thyroid and adrenal system.
These are adaptation systems.
So, nervous,
vascular, glandular. And the glandular system, in its proper function, will be
dependent on the connective system. This means that to release a
connective system, to release an endocrine system, I need to work on my fascial tissue,
dietary. Don't forget that there was a timeline of emergence. Thus, we already retain
that the entire digestive system is suspended at the base
of the skull. We can
imagine it like a rope.
I ring the bell, you see, my digestive system
is suspended, and we will see how it is suspended by the fascial system up to my
base of the skull.
We have a tissue that divides into a limiting tissue and an
internal tissue.
This means that the most important here will be my limiting tissue.
We will study in this limiting tissue the endoderm, and we see that the endoderm is ultimately
an epithelium.
It is a boundary tissue,
so it is a tissue
of exchange.
I exchange with my mesoderm,
it is the one that contains the primary information.
It is the royal road.
I exchange through this.
The tissue is an epithelial tissue
of endoderm like the ectoderm.
It is an epithelium tissue,
so that's why it's a tissue
of limits.
In the limiting tissue, there is never
any congestion. Congestions
are always treated on the mesodermal plane. So,
our tissue is mesodermic, and it bears
among other things all your vascular systems. The second important thing is the tissue
of endoderm, the epithelial tissue
whether they are two types of boundaries, either endodermic or ectodermic limits,
it is the one that carries the glandular system.
In other words, all glands always derive from your
limiting tissue.
So all glands are always tissues
that have an epithelial origin.
You have many glands.
We can consider that, for example, at the thyroid level, it is a gland.
But we can consider that your lungs are glands.
We can consider that your liver is a gland.
They are expansions of your epithelial tube.
It's an epithelial endoderm.
So keep in mind that my endoderm will give,
and that my ectoderm, through my epithelial system, carries my hormonal plan.
Don't forget,
The hormonal system goes deeply into the body.
It is dependent on my system, among other things, very much on the digestive or ectodermic system.
Very much digestive.
This phrase is what you need to remember.
The internal tissue is both the engine and
the resistance to growth to limit the tissues in their development.
I will call this the algorithm.
for development.
That is, it's a repetitive system.
This means that at some point,
the growth speeds do not match the same speed within the tissue.
And these growth speeds will give us support points,
which are points, what we call hitchpons.
When you have hitchpons,
you have hinges for general organization.
And we, the body,
need to, the body knows what it needs to do, there is no problem for it.
However, we need to support its process.
And to support its process, we need to return to ontogenetic qualities,
qualities where the tissue can reorganize.
A fulcrum is a support point for the creation of a form
and it always remains present.
For example, it is also a fulcrum between a point of balance.
between a moment where I have a change.
First major articulation in the body.
I have my vascular system, meaning my two primitive vessels that are present.
The internal tissue, namely the mesodermic tissue,
what does it contain?
The mesodermic tissue contains vessels.
These vessels will develop in an embryo early on.
This means that at the moment I have my notochord, I see the emergence laterally, relative
to my neural plate, of a reorganization of my fluid system of the body. So this
re-integration
of my fluid system implies that my internal system brings
energy, so it is an engine, but it does not grow at
the same speed, so
it is a brake. My ectoderm behind it, it grows super fast because
it is very nourished. So, I represent my ectoderm. Here,
what do I see? I
see my heart or the area of the primitive cardiac congestion that is above my head, meaning in the caudal part of my embryo. The
ectoderm, which is my body,
grows much faster than this area. I grow, I grow, and there is a brake here
in front.
Well, I come to wrap around
my cardiac zone, going backward, if
you look, the heart here, in the process of development,
it does not grow at the same speed, so it becomes a global support point
for development.
This means that my first fulcrum will be on this heart and my spheno-basilar symphysis.
This global movement of development becomes like an organization plan, like
an articulation plan.
articulations and you will see that all my articulations are just repetitions
of the same sequential process of this algorithm. A kidney on a liver is an articulation,
a lung on a diaphragm, a lung on a heart are phases of articulation.
Why can I flex like this and why can’t I flex like that? Because
I have an olecranon. But before, there was no olecranon, yet I still could
go that way. Why? I wrap towards my vascular system. Here I have an artery.
There, I do not have one. And what do I do? I do this. If I had an artery here, I would have the capacity to
go that way.
And look here, it is the same thing. And you see what a little embryo does in
the beginning? It comes to wrap around like this.
Completely. And you will see that your brain will follow vascular fields of development.
Last time, we studied this development of the brain. We did the brain tai chi. Remember
we will do it again later
and we will integrate it this time
with the digestive system
because not only what happens there
happens here synchronously
and we will start to see
that what happens here
can be a phenomenon that blocks here
and that treating, for example,
a line here will release
a visceral articulation
or vice versa.
the navel
you eliminate
completely maintained here at the moment you enter the uterine earth
that you embody this first
moment, this first contact it is this seeking here, it is an enormous contact you
are in and that
it is always done in a very specific pole, you remember it always happens on
a
assimilation plane, this means that it is a plane you remember I talked about polarity
we talked about polarity
One of the first things the embryo did was polarity.
At the moment I enter this mucosa, I enter through an organized electrical, electromagnetic field.
I am not entering in a disorganized way, I always enter the same way,
through my assimilation plan, through the plane where I seek trophic information.
So I arrive, this first contact is an important contact with the mother, the embryonic
pedicle.
And the final umbilical cord will be the
vestige here of the yolk sac with the
embryonic pedicle.
Both together will form this umbilical cord.
So the umbilical cord, the navel here, will be the
meeting between this primitive phase of integration of
your incarnation.
in the uterine flesh
with this first contact that will be made
and then we will see later
with the development of my cavity
of the integration of my
external coelom into an internal coelom
and more specifically
even before
it is the establishment of Heusser’s membrane
with the establishment
of my yolk sac and my
external coelom
that will form this S
of organization in autocorrelation
that will give back the integration towards my attachment at the level
of my global system.
Because your intestine and your body are a symbol.
And they carry the symbolism of your words.
Not just anywhere.
You have realized your symbol or you have remained in your diabolical state.
Am I scattered or am I focused, gathered?
I was able to gather myself.
And many people are still in the diabolism of their integration because
they haven’t found the symbol. There are many people who leave the symbol.